Guide to the Wiltwyck School for Boys records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Executive Director Files, 1942-1981
  - Subseries 2: Subject Files, 1965-1981
    - Urban League, National, 1977-1978 (Box 42, Folder 1013)
      - Westchester (Box 43, Folder 1024)
        - County, 1979-1980 (Box 43, Folder 1027)
          - Mental Health Board, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 1030)
        - Friends of Wiltwyck, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 1031)
        - Institute of Services for Children, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 1032)
        - Putnam School Boards Association, 1979-1980 (Box 43, Folder 1033)
      - White, Lewis A., 1969 (Box 43, Folder 1034)
      - Wildcat Service Corporation, 1975-1976 (Box 43, Folder 1035)
      - Wilder/Sugarman, 1973-1975, (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 1036-1037)
      - Willia Hardgrow Mental Health Clinic, 1978-1979 (Box 43, Folder 1038)
      - Wiltwyck
        - General, 1974-1979, (7 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 1039-1045)
        - Administration, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 1046)
        - Administration Board-Staff Committee,1969 (Box 43, Folder 1047)
        - Alumni, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 1048)
        - Annual Reports, 1967 July 1-1968 June 30 (Box 43, Folder 1049)
        - Anticipated Projects,1965 (Box 43, Folder 1050)
        - Background, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 1051)
        - Benefits and Press Releases, undated (Box 43, Folder 1052)
        - Board of Directors: Finance Committee,1966 (Box 44, Folder 1053)
        - Budget Presentations, 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 1054)
        - Business Procedures, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 1055)
        - By-laws and Certificates of Incorporation, 1942-1953 (Box 44, Folder 1056)
        - Campus Committee, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 1057)
        - Executive Council, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 1058)
        - Experience Evaluations, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 1059)
        - Five-Year Plan, 1975-1980 (Box 44, Folder 1060)
        - Group Home Program Manual, undated (Box 44, Folder 1061)
        - History, Appendix I, undated (Box 44, Folder 1062)
        - Lease Information, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 1063)
        - New York Office, Martin Hellman, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 1064)
        - Non-discrimination Policy, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 1065)
        - Organizational Policy, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 1066)
        - Parents' Group, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 1067)
        - Perspectives, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 1068)
        - Policies and Procedures, undated (Box 44, Folder 1069)
        - Population Information, undated (Box 44, Folder 1070)
        - Proposal, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 1071)
        - School Report, 1974 June 30 (Box 44, Folder 1072)
        - Special Budget Report, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 1073)
        - Tables of Organization,1979-1980 (Box 44, Folder 1074)
      - Work-Release Programs, 1979-1980 (Box 44, Folder 1075)
      - Yorktown Union Free School District, 1967-1978, (4 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 1076-1079)
      - Yorktown Union Free School District, 1973-1981, (9 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 1080-1088)
        - Board Meetings, 1971-1975, (3 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 1089-1091)
        - Board Meetings, 1977-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 1092-1093)
        - Board Reorganization, 1973 (Box 46, Folder 1094)
        - Curriculum and Goals, 1974-1975 (Box 46, Folder 1095)
      - Yorktown, Town of, 1979-1980, (2 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 1096-1097)
  - Series III: Staff Articles and Publications, 1963-1979
    Series III is comprised of articles and conference papers by Wiltwyck staff and also by unaffiliated authors. Most articles and conference papers deal with the particular demographic served by Wiltwyck and often include case studies drawn from Wiltwyck patients.
    - Wiltwyck Staff Articles General, 1964-1978, (3 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 1098-1100)
      - B-D, 1974-1975 (Box 46, Folder 1101)
      - E, 1976 (Box 47, Folder 1102)
      - F-H, 1968-1976 (Box 47, Folder 1103)
      - J-K, 1973-1975 (Box 47, Folder 1104)
      - M-Sc, 1975-1976 (Box 47, Folder 1105)
    - Minuchin, Salvador, "Families with Multiple Acting-Out Boys,"1963 (Box 47, Folder 1106)
      - Silcott, T. George, General, 1969-1974, (2 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 1107)
      - A-F, 1972-1979 (Box 47, Folder 1108)
      - Fu-R, 1976-1977 (Box 48, Folder 1109)
      - S-T, 1969-1979 (Box 48, Folder 1110)
      - V-W, 1975 (Box 48, Folder 1111)
    - Wiltwyck Staff Articles--Bibliographies, 1972 (Box 48, Folder 1112)
  - Series IV: Printed Material, 1966-1975
    This series includes printed material produced by Wiltwyck: yearbooks, benefit programs, and published descriptive material. This series also contains a photo-book of Eleanor Roosevelt that emphasizes her role at Wiltwyck.
    - Eleanor Roosevelt Campus in the Architectural Record, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 1113)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt--Her Day, 1973 (Box 48, Folder 1114)
    - Benefit Programs, 1966-1972 (Box 48, Folder 1115)
    - Volunteer Manual, undated (Box 48, Folder 1116)
    - Wiltwyck Annual Report, 1970-1975 (Box 48, Folder 1117)
    - Wiltwyck Journal, 1974-1975 (Box 48, Folder 1118)
    - Wiltwyck News, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 1119)
    - Wiltwyck Story, 1966 (Box 48, Folder 1120)
  - Series V: Oversize Material, 1965-1981
    Series V contains architectural blueprints and drawings for Eleanor Roosevelt Campus, oversize clippings, and a ledger of statistics on patients.
    - Bloom, Daniel, Fish Relief Chart, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 1121)
    - Dream Lake Campus: Plans and Interior Furnishings 1964 (Box 49, Folder 1122)
    - Fundraising and Public Relations, 1980-1981, (2 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 1123-1124)
    - Ledger, Patient Listing July 1965- May 1976 (Box 49, Folder 1125)
    - Ledger, Statistics January 1966 (Box 49, Folder 1126)
    - Real Estate 1975-6 (Box 49, Folder 1127)
    - Architectural plans, patient records, clippings (Box Flat Box 748)